Hey.
你…
Are you being serious?
是認真的嗎？
There is no other way out of our financial difficulties.
想要解決財務危機 我們沒有其他辦法了
The way forward for Tatsumi Gakuen
龍海學園要繼續下去
is to get students into the University of Tokyo.
只能把學生送到東京大學
If we can get several students into Japan's top university,
要是能把幾個學生 送進日本的頂尖大學
Tatsumi Gakuen will become a household name nationwide.
龍海學園就會在全國家喻戶曉
Applications for admission will skyrocket.
入學申請也會迅速劇增
This year's admissions are at 60% of capacity.
今年的入學人數不到招生名額的六成
We have seven classes of third years.
三年級有七班
Five classes of second years.
二年級有五班
And fewer than half new first years, at just three classes.
一年級的新生只有三班
With the UTokyo halo effect, student numbers will grow.
東大的明星效應會帶動入學人數
This is our only way to survive.
這是我們唯一能夠存活的方法
UTokyo? Are you serious?
東大？你是認真的嗎？
Look at the reality. Reality!
面對現實吧，現實！
Our school's deviation score is 32!
我校的平均分數才32分！
Our students can't get into any top universities, let alone UTokyo!
別說東大了 這些學生進入頂尖大學的機率是零
Do your dreaming when you're asleep.
醒著就不要做夢
Alright then, let's hear your idea!
那你來說說你有什麼方法啊！
-Come on, ideas! -Yeah!
-說啊！ -對啊！
Our livelihoods are on the line!
我們的生計可是命懸一線！
Student numbers drop every year.
學生人數每年下降
And teachers are made to leave.
教師被迫離開
Over these three years, a third have been let go.
三年間已經流失了三分之一
I can't take it not knowing when I might be next!
我真受不了 想著下一個會不會是自己的感覺
But UTokyo is nonsense.
但是，東大簡直就是無稽之談
It's nothing more than a pipe dream.
根本就是白日夢
Only 30% of our students intend to enter university.
我們的學生中只有三成有意願進大學
We're one of the dumbest schools in the prefecture.
我們是這個縣最笨的學校之一
Sending multiple students to UTokyo?
把幾個學生送去東大？
It's an insult to UTokyo.
真是侮辱東大
Chairman, what do you think?
理事長，妳有什麼看法？
Naturally, I'm against it.
我自然是反對的
But to escape this crisis,
但要擺脫這個危機
we must first improve students' academic ability
我們首先必須改善學生的成績…
Academic ability.
成績…
Binding children with the selfish values of adults?
把小孩和大人 自私的價值觀捆綁在一起？
Not while I'm in charge.
我在位時可不允許
The ones in charge of this sloppy country now
現在掌控這不像樣的國家的人們
are UTokyo graduates who studied so much they can't think flexibly.
正是那些書讀太多 無法靈活思考的東大畢業生
I want to help our students grow their abilities and individuality,
我要幫學生培養他們的才能和個性
and help this country be reborn.
讓這個國家重生
I'll make a name for Tatsumi Gakuen as a high school that makes future leaders.
我會把龍海學園 打造成培養未來領袖的高中
We'll go under before those ideals are achieved.
在實現妳這些理想之前 我們就要倒閉了
We'll be bankrupt in three years.
我們三年內會破產
Acceptance into UTokyo is our way out of bankruptcy.
東大入學可以讓我們避免破產
Getting ranked here, and improving our reputation is the only way.
在這裡得到名次 和提高聲譽是唯一的辦法
We'll accept nationwide applicants, and next year break our low enrollment streak.
我們將收到來自全國的申請 明年就會終止
We'll put an end to it.
三年招不滿學生的紀錄
Next year?
明年？
Nobody can get into UTokyo in one year!
怎麼可能在一年培養出東大生？
It's possible.
那是可能的
Do you know about my previous high school?
大家知道我之前在哪所高中就職嗎？
No, where were you?
不知道，是哪所？
Ryuzan High School.
龍山高中
Ryuzan?
龍山？
That's a famous, high-level school!
那不是很有名的升學學校嗎？
Yes, now it is. But it used to be lower than here.
對，現在是 不過它曾經比這裡還要糟糕
-Their deviation score was just 30. -Thirty?
-平均分數曾經只有30分 -30？
With just one lawyer, it was reborn into a regular producer of UTokyo entrants.
只憑一位律師 它變身固定產出東大入學生的高中
Now it's a famous school flooded with applicants.
現在它已經是大家搶著要進去的名校
Where is he now?
那人現在在哪裡？
He put Ryuzan on track, then left.
他把龍山整治好後就離開了
After that, he had many offers.
那之後，他收到很多邀請
He took on just one school that was on its last legs.
他只接受了一間學校 那間學校已經快要倒閉了
That high school also got back on its feet.
那間學校也重新站了起來
We'll get that lawyer to come to our school.
我們會把那位律師請到我們學校
Wait. Are you talking about Tsurumaki High, from two years ago?
等一下 難道你說的是兩年前的弦卷高中？
You're kidding!
不會吧？
That man was all over tabloid TV.
那時報紙和電視都在報導那男人
No! No! No! Not that man!
不…那男人不可以！
He's already here.
他已經在這裡了
The lawyer who's a former bike gang member, right?
那個曾是暴走族的律師，對嗎？
But he's the only one who can save our school now.
但他現在是唯一可以拯救我們的人
Mr. Kenji Sakuragi. He's the only one who--
櫻木建二老師，他是唯一一個…
Pardon me. Vice principal?
不好意思，教務主任
Thank you.
麻煩了
I'm from Mizuno Law Office.
我來自水野律師事務所
My name is Naomi Mizuno, attorney-at-law. I'm pleased to meet you.
我是律師水野直美，請大家多指教
-Mizuno… -Mizuno?
-水野… -水野？
Mr. Takahara! Long time no see.
高原老師！好久不見了
Yes, yes. But where is Mr. Sakuragi?
對，那個…櫻木老師呢？
It was so sudden, there was no room in his schedule.
事出突然，他日程裡沒有空檔了
Sakuragi is currently on another case.
櫻木正在負責另一起案件
-I'm here on his behalf. -I see.
-所以我先代替他過來 -原來如此
Alright Mizuno, ah, Ms. Mizuno. This way.
那麼水野，啊…水野老師，請過來
Mr. Takahara. You're vice principal now! Wow!
高原老師 你現在是教務主任了，真厲害！
You were so unimpressive that I had no memory of you, but now look!
你以前太不起眼了 我都不記得你，但你看看現在！
I'm a lawyer now! I was so stupid, but look!
我現在是個律師了 我曾經那麼笨，但看看現在！
Ms. Mizuno. This is Chairman Tatsuno.
水野老師，這是龍野理事長
Sakuragi couldn't come in person today.
櫻木今天無法親自過來
-For that, I am sorry. -Is that true?
-對此我很抱歉 -是真的嗎？
Word is he hasn't been working for years.
聽說他已經很多年沒教書了
It's alright.
沒問題的
He is busy as we speak, preparing for your school's request.
我們在說話的時候 他正在忙著準備你們學校的請求
Could you ask the principal of Tsurumaki High School?
你能問問看弦卷高中的校長嗎？
Right away.
明白了
FUKUI PREFECTURE
（福井縣）
-Damn it. -Alright! Caught another one!
-可惡 -好耶！又抓了一隻！
It's huge! Huge!
好大一條！真大一條！
Alright! Look!
好耶！看看！
NO FISHING ZONE
（禁止釣魚區域）
It's huge! Huge!
真大，真大啊！
Black seabream!
黑鯛啊黑鯛！
You are a liar.
妳是個騙子
This says whereabouts unknown.
這寫著他現在下落不明
-Mizuno! -Well…
-水野 -這個嘛…
He gets so many calls, he has sort of gone into hiding…
每天接到太多電話，他好像躲起來了
Enough with the bald-faced lies.
別再睜眼說瞎話了
We can't hire someone if we don't even know if he's alive or dead.
是死是活都不知道的人，我們不能請
You mock me.
妳這是把我當笨蛋
I have nothing more to say to you.
看來沒什麼好跟妳談的了
Wait. Could you at least discuss it at the next board meeting?
請等一下，至少下次理事會 能不能討論這件事？
We teaching staff all agree, we want to become a high-level school.
我們教職員一致同意想成為升學學校
You all agree? Who agrees?
同意？你們誰同意？
About 60% are in favor.
大約六成都贊成
Articles of endowment say a majority request
章程規定，多數人的要求
must be discussed by the board.
必須被列入理事會的議程
Chairman.
理事長
There may be a majority, but until I meet this man, the board won't discuss it.
就算大多數人同意，沒見到這男人前 理事會不討論這個方案
TATSUMI GAKUEN HIGH SCHOOL
（龍海學園高中）
That's so irritating. Who does she think she is?
真是煩人，那女人以為自己是誰啊？
You still can't find him?
你還找不到他嗎？
Give me a break, senpai.
妳也饒了我吧，前輩
He's been off the grid for two years. He won't be easy to find.
他都消失了兩年 哪會那麼容易讓人找到？
What?
什麼？
For anyone but me, I mean.
我的意思是 對其他人來說啦，但難不倒我
Let me say this, it'll cost you.
我先跟妳說，這情報很貴的
I'll pay whatever it takes. Please help me, President Sakamoto.
多少錢我都會付 求你幫我了，坂本社長
Yes.
好
20 HOURS LATER
（20小時後）
Yeah! Got one!
耶！抓到一隻！
C'mon!
好，來啊！
I've been watching. You didn't catch anything today or yesterday.
我一直在看你 你今天和昨天都沒收穫啊
Fishing is all about location. It's all one sea, but the place matters.
釣魚的關鍵是位置，雖是同一片海 但釣魚的地點很重要啊
You've got to collect information. Just like life.
你得掌握更多情報，就像人生
Gotta use your noggin.
得動腦筋啊
Hey, look at this.
看看
See?
看到了嗎？
You're no fun. Anyway, good luck with the fish.
你真是無趣！算了，祝你好運
Ouch, ow! What's this?
哎呀！好燙！這是什麼？
Oh, a blowfish? Gross little thing.
河豚？真噁心
What the hell?
什麼鬼啊？
Hey.
喂
Hang on, was that your lunch?
等一下，那是你的午餐？
Sorry.
對不起
What?
什麼？
I'll give you one.
我可以給你一條
-Two? -Nice.
-兩條？ -很好
Go ahead.
拿去吧
Hey! What are you doing?
喂！你幹什麼？
Stop that! Don't! Screw you, asshole!
快停手！不要！ 去你的，你這個混帳！
Speak up. Say something.
你說點什麼啊
-Say something, asshole! -Now, now!
-說話啊，混帳！ -好了…
If you don't tell us the reason, you'll have to be detained at the station.
你不說原因，我們就得拘留你
You want that?
你要這樣嗎？
Stop!
請等一下！
You're saying that this man threw away the fish that you caught, right?
你剛剛說這個男人 把你釣的魚都丟掉，對嗎？
What of it?
所以呢？
But your fishing spot on the embankment is a no-fishing zone.
但你釣魚的堤岸可是禁漁區
NO FISHING ZONE
（禁止釣魚區域）
-Isn't that right? -Uh, yeah.
-我說得對嗎？ -嗯，對的
According to the other fishermen, you always fish in that spot.
根據另一位漁夫的說法 你常在那個地點釣魚
That's because… uh, you know.
那是因為…那又怎樣？
That's a violation of the Fisheries and Minor Offenses Act.
這違反了《漁業法》和《輕犯罪法》
In other words, you're the one who should be arrested.
換句話說，應該被逮捕的人是你才對
You're already done eating?
你已經吃完了？
Wow. The pork cutlet is sticking out. Looks good.
這豬排都滿出來了，看起來真好吃
It's not good. That's just the batter coating.
才不好吃，那只是炸麵糊而已
The meat is thin, and the frying oil is old so it smells weird.
肉薄，油也放久了，有股怪味！
I pay for your meal, and that's what you say?
我請你吃飯耶，有必要說成這樣？
Here's your second helping of pork cutlet on rice.
你的第二份豬排飯到了
You say that, and you're on your second helping?
你剛剛說什麼，還點第二份？
I haven't seen you in ages. I was expecting more reaction.
好久沒見了，你就沒有更多反應嗎？
It's been two years. If you see a student after two years,
都兩年了，時隔兩年見到一個學生
you say "Have you been well?" or "You got prettier!"
“妳好嗎？”或者“妳變漂亮了”
"Thanks for helping me back there!" You could say that.
“謝謝妳剛剛幫忙”，你都不說嗎？
I can tell you've been well by looking at you.
看妳的樣子就知道過得不錯
I don't think you got prettier. And you didn't help me.
我不覺得妳變漂亮了 妳剛剛也沒有幫到我
I knew he was fishing in a no-fishing zone.
我知道他在禁漁區釣魚
I got myself arrested so the police would feed me lunch.
我讓自己被抓是為了在警局吃午飯
What you've done is harmed your client's interests.
妳做的事損害了妳當事人的利益
You say that to the person who bought your lunch and clothes?
你就跟請你吃飯 給你買衣服的人說這種話？
Sir, won't you come back to work?
老師，你不回來工作嗎？
I opened a law office.
我開了個律師事務所
-I could hire you. -No.
-老師，我可以請你 -我拒絕
There's a case that I think you'd be interested in.
有個案件我覺得老師會感興趣
Do you know of Tatsumi Gakuen in Chiba?
你聽過千葉縣的龍海學園嗎？
They're famous for badminton--
他們的羽毛球很有名…
I don't know that stupid school.
我沒聽過那笨蛋學校
You do know it then!
那你就是聽過了！
You're avoiding my eyes.
你在躲避我的眼神
They have a deviation score of 40, right?
平均分數只有40的笨蛋學校吧？
Now it's 32.
現在是32分了
Three years ago, daughter Kumiko took over as chairman from her father, Kyojiro.
三年前，龍野久美子 接替她父親龍野恭二郎擔任理事長
Both applicant numbers and academic levels are on the decline.
入學人數和學業成績雙雙下滑
In the name of increasing student autonomy,
以學生自治的名義
they eliminated homework, and the academic level has plummeted.
他們廢除了功課和課外補習 此後學業成績就下降了
And?
然後？
They've requested your services.
他們提出要老師你的協助
No.
我拒絕
My fate depends on successfully revitalizing the school.
我的命運就靠著 能不能成功復活這間學校了
Your fate?
妳的命運？
After you left the office two years ago, I've been working my butt off.
兩年前，你離開事務所後 我拼了命工作
I established the Mizuno Law Office,
我創立了水野律師事務所
taking any job I could, and I finally got this chance!
什麼工作都接，終於有了這個機會！
Mizuno Law Office?
水野律師事務所？
Aren't you ashamed? Making your own student pay for you.
你就不覺得丟臉嗎？ 讓你的學生給你付錢？
And you don't even listen to what I need! That's low!
你甚至沒在聽我需要什麼！ 真是可惡！
Hang on! What are you doing? In a place like this?
等一下…你在幹嘛？ 居然在這種地方？
If you want it back, you can have it.
如果妳要，我就還給妳啊
Do you want the food back too?
食物妳也要我還給妳嗎？
You don't have to give it back! Just put your clothes back on!
不用還啦！求求你把衣服穿回去！
Sir! Are you finished?
老師，你好了嗎？
That asshole!
這個混帳！
Mister Ahmed!
阿末先生
What are you doing? Faking a name and nationality?
你在幹嘛？弄了個假名和假國籍？
I'll handle your back rent.
我會解決你欠的租金
So you--
所以你…
You can't pay rent. Even your water got cut off.
你付不了租金，連水都斷了
-You can't even afford food. -Oh, right.
-你甚至連食物都買不起 -該死
Do you plan to stay in ruins like this?
你打算一直住在這樣的廢墟裡嗎？
The conditions of the Tatsumi Gakuen job are not bad compared to two years ago.
龍海學園那份工作的條件 不比兩年前差
In fact, they're exceptional.
不如說條件很好
Let's build a reputation, and go back to the office in Toranomon.
我們把名聲建立回來 然後回去虎之門的事務所吧
I'll do all the hard work. And if that's not enough,
我會做完所有苦差事 這樣還不夠的話
you can just be an advisor if you let me use your name.
如果你願意讓我用你的名字 你可以只當個顧問
How about it? Sir.
怎麼樣，老師？
Do you plan to keep walking into your bleak, dark future?
你的人生要這樣 往陰冷又黑暗的方向去嗎？
What? Sir, was your power cut off?
什麼？老師，你連電都斷了？
-It's 800,000 yen. -Eight hundred?
-八十萬日圓 -八十？
-That's what I owe. -What? No way.
-那是我欠的數目 -什麼？騙人的吧
-This run-down apartment? -Can you pay?
-在這種破爛公寓？ -妳會付？
-I'll pay. -And get me a new suit.
-我會付… -再給我一套新的西裝
Shoes and shirts, a necktie, and all the rest.
皮鞋、襯衫、領帶，還有其他剩下的
-That's 200,000 yen. -Two hundred?
-那是二十萬 -二十萬？
Didn't I just buy you a new one?
我剛剛不是才給你買了一套？
Hey, hey!
等一下…
When you're my size,
我這種體型
you gotta get them order made.
需要特別訂做
You damn giant!
你這個巨人！
I need a phone too. Listen, my take is half of the fee.
我還需要一台手機 聽著，我要妳一半的酬勞
I'm just an advisor. You do the work.
我只是個顧問，實際的工作妳來做
Okay, I'll do it.
行了，我知道了
You bet. Seven days a week.
那說好了，一週七天
Breakfast, lunch and dinner. Don't forget.
不要忘記我的早、午、晚餐
See ya.
再見
In order to bring them to the school,
要將兩位請到學校
we must first get approval from the board of directors.
我們得先經過理事會的同意
There are five members of the board.
理事會由五位成員組成
First is the current chairman, Kumiko Tatsuno.
第一位是現任理事長龍野久美子
Her supporter, Principal Okuda.
她的支持者奧田校長
Former principal Komatsugawa,
前任校長小松先生
and Chairman Kumiko's father, former chairman Kyojiro Tatsuno.
還有久美子理事長的父親 前任理事長龍野恭二郎
Her father was the chairman?
她父親是前任理事長？
Yes. He brought along an education critic formerly of the Ministry of Education.
是的，跟隨他的是 曾在文科省任職的教育評論家
Mr. Shinpei Hibino.
日比野晉平
I see how this will go.
看得出事情會怎麼發展
Two votes from the family, two from her cronies.
龍野家族兩票，她的親信再投兩票
The critic the father brought will also be on their side. Five, zero.
她父親帶來的評論家 也會在他們那邊，五比零
Actually, it's not so simple.
老實說，沒有那麼簡單
Sorry I'm late, Kumiko.
抱歉我遲到了，久美子
Call me "Chairman" here, former chairman.
在這裡請叫我理事長，前理事長
Discord within the family, is it?
家族不和，是嗎？
Yes, the former chairman and Mr. Hibino are in favor.
是的，前理事長 和日比野先生站同一陣線
Then it's two versus three.
那是二比三
We're still outnumbered.
我們還是不夠票
Even if we can't change the empress' mind,
就算我們不能改變女皇的想法…
Alright, this proposal by Mr. Takahara.
好，這是高原先生的提案
Let's hear about this education consultant.
我們來聽聽這位教育顧問怎麼樣
If I mention the law office that had a scandal two years ago,
那家律師事務所兩年前的醜聞
I think you know it.
我想你也知道
Setbacks make people stronger.
挫折讓人變得更強大
I think Mr. Sakuragi sounds promising.
我覺得櫻木先生聽起來大有作為
Don't you all think so?
你們不覺得嗎？
As for the two principals, when the former chairman was in power,
前理事長當權的時候，另外兩位校長
they had just been hired, so he has pull with them.
才剛被聘用 所以他對他們有點影響力
I will give my opinion
我在下星期的理事例會
at next week's regular board meeting.
再提出看法
I will convince one of them before the regular board meeting.
下次理事例會之前 我會說服他們其中一位
I'll find a way to get that precious vote.
我會想辦法拿到那珍貴的一票
-We're depending on you. -Yes.
-拜託你了 -是的
This case is no good.
這案件不好辦啊
What about it?
怎麼這樣說？
I don't think he can convince those two before the meeting.
我不覺得 他能在下次會議前說服那兩位
Lemme get my daily wages.
我來拿日薪啦
Hey.
喂
Damn it…
可惡
After paying for your rent and suit, it's empty.
付了你的租金和西裝費後就空了
Since I'm focusing on the Tatsumi Gakuen contract,
再說我為了專注在龍海學園的案子上
I've turned down all other little jobs.
已經推掉所有的小案子了
Okay, go sleep with them.
那麼，去跟他們睡啊
One of the principals will take you up.
其中一個校長會要妳的
Huh? I'll sue you for real!
什麼？我要告你！
I mean, I could get them both in one try.
再說要是我出馬 我能把他們兩個一次弄到手
If we get this, that contract fee will be fat and juicy.
如果談得成，合約金可是很誘人的
There must be a way…
總有方法的吧
Maybe I can seduce one of them…
就沒辦法說服理事長派的人嗎？
Thank you for making time to decide on my proposal today.
感謝大家抽時間來考慮我的提案
-I first offer my thanks. -No need for speeches.
-我首先跟大家致謝… -省下演講的時間吧
Hurry up and take the vote.
快說重點，我們接著投票
Those in favor of Sakuragi and Mizuno making a UTokyo special course,
那麼同意櫻木和水野開設東大專科
and using their success to rebuild the school's reputation,
讓他們用之前成功的經驗 重建學校聲譽的理事
raise your hand.
請舉手
The two who haven't raised their hands are with me in opposition, correct?
沒有舉手的兩位 和我一樣投反對，對嗎？
Well then, this motion has failed.
那麼，這個動議就失敗…
-Please wait a moment. -What?
-請等一下 -什麼？
I would like to try hiring Mr. Sakuragi.
我想試試聘請櫻木老師
Three in favor, and two opposed.
三位同意，兩位反對
It's decided.
結論出來了
This is completely unacceptable.
我絕對不能接受
No matter what, I want to make a school of freedom, not bound by studying.
無論如何，我想辦的是一間 不被學習束縛，自由的學校
The board's decision is absolute.
理事會的決定已成定局
To reject that is unheard of in the history of the school.
龍海學園的校史上 從來沒有推翻過理事會的決定
You're not even in the Tatsuno family. Don't talk like you are.
你不是龍海家族的人 別用這種語氣跟我說話
All you talk about is freedom this, freedom that.
妳嘴邊總是掛著“自由”
But when they enter the world, strict discipline and competition awaits.
這些學生進入社會 等著他們的卻是嚴格的紀律和競爭
Adults who know that truth well
分明知道這真相的成年人
building a school based on freedom alone?
竟然想僅憑自由建立學校？
I wouldn't want my child to go there.
我不會願意送我孩子到那種學校
I was raised strictly and forced into UTokyo.
我被嚴格養大，又被逼著進入東大
Do I look like I'm living a free life?
我看起來像過著自由的生活嗎？
I will stake my career as an educator on making this a high-level school.
我以教師生涯作為賭注 我會把這裡打造成升學學校
Okay, how many will you get into UTokyo?
好，多少人會進東大？
In our first year, we'll start with one.
第一年，我們先從一位開始
All this grandstanding for just one?
那麼興師動眾，你只送去一位？
Three then, no…
那麼，三位…不…
Five people.
五位
Five people? That's impossible.
五位？不可能
Alright, five. Get five students into UTokyo in a year,
好，五位 一年內把五位學生送到東大
or you're fired.
要不然你就被開除了
-What? -But if five students pass?
-什麼？ -但如果五位學生真的考上了呢？
Kumiko.
久美子
You'll have to quit as chairman.
妳就得辭掉理事長一職
You said it would be impossible, right?
妳剛剛說絕對不可能，對吧？
If you have any pride as an educator,
如果妳還有身為教育者的尊嚴
you'll bet your life on it too.
就把人生賭進來
Uh, yes.
嗯，是
A high-level school,
升學學校
or a free school culture.
或是自由的校風
Show me which future this school should pursue.
讓我看看這所學校 未來會朝哪個方向前進
Kaede, can we go?
楓，還沒好嗎？
Go on ahead.
妳先去
Hurry or you'll be late for the opening ceremonies.
快點哦，不然會錯過開學典禮的
Okay.
好
What are you doing?
妳在幹嘛？
Oh, it's just you.
什麼啊，原來是你
Oh, if you want it you can have it.
哦，想要的話，這個可以給你
You're not the type to do that.
妳不是會做這種事的人
What, a lecture?
你在幹嘛？說教？
I'm telling you to stop shoplifting!
我是說，別再偷東西了！
Oh, shoplifting?
哦？偷東西？
What do you want?
有什麼事嗎？
Shoplifting is great. What a thrill.
偷東西很好啊，真是刺激
You're mistaken about the shoplifting.
你聽錯了，沒有人偷東西
Mr. Sakuragi, what are you doing?! The opening ceremonies are starting.
櫻木老師，你在這裡做什麼？ 開學典禮快要開始了
Is that my breakfast?
那是我的早餐嗎？
They're gifts for the staff room.
那是給教職員的禮物
I told you to wait by the gate.
我不是叫你在大門等我嗎？
Where's my food?
我的食物呢？
A teacher?
老師？
-Go buy something! -We're going!
-去買些什麼啊！ -我們要走了！
Man.
真是的
I feel like the wrong guy saw that.
好像讓麻煩的人看到了
We welcome a new educational consultant to Tatsumi Gakuen,
歡迎這位教育顧問來到龍海學園
attorney Ms. Mizuno. Ms. Mizuno, please.
律師水野老師，請說，水野老師
Um.
呃
Nice to meet you, everyone.
初次見面，大家好
I'm Naomi Mizuno.
我是水野直美
Myself,
我，還有
and Kenji Sakuragi, attorney-at-law have come here for just one reason.
那邊的櫻木建二律師來這裡 只為了一個目的
That is to get you accepted into UTokyo.
那就是讓你們考進東大
Starting this year, third-year students
因此今年開始，針對三年級的學生
will have a newly established course.
設立了一個全新的班級
Its name is…
班級的名稱是…
the UTokyo Special Course!
東大專科！
It's a lot to take in.
大家，資訊量是不是有點多呢？
I completely understand.
我完全可以明白
Who, me? UTokyo?
“妳說誰？我？東大？”
I'm sure you feel this way.
我想各位心裡正這樣想著
But it's okay.
但沒關係的
When I was in high school, my deviation score was 30.
其實高中時，我平均只有30分
She's an idiot.
根本就是笨蛋
But I studied under Mr. Sakuragi's guidance,
但我在櫻木老師的指導下學習
and I got into UTokyo.
考進了東大
I want everyone to shoot for UTokyo.
所以我希望大家把東大當作目標
Believe in us, and come with us.
相信我們，跟著我們
If you work hard, a path will open up.
只要努力，一定有方法的
Okay? Everyone.
好嗎，大家？
Ugly and stupid can go to UTokyo!
笨蛋和醜女也可以上東大！
Just kidding.
開玩笑的啦
That's all.
我講完了
Thank you, Ms. Mizuno.
水野老師，謝謝妳
What was that?
那是怎樣啊？
Funny.
真好笑
Now, a word from educational supervisor, Mr. Sakuragi.
現在，請教育顧問櫻木老師上台致辭
Mr. Sakuragi, go ahead.
櫻木老師，請
Mr. Sakuragi!
櫻木老師！
Knock one out of the park.
好好表現！
I'm counting on you!
全靠你了！
What a bunch of sad sacks.
真是一堆可悲的傢伙
Idiots these days are too dumb to even look dumb.
現在的白痴太蠢了，連個蠢樣都沒有
Listen, all of you.
你們全部給我聽著
No matter what, don't go to UTokyo.
不管怎樣，別給我去東大
What?
-什麼？
What's up with him?
他怎麼回事？
Mr. Sakuragi has deep intentions
櫻木老師這樣說是有其他意思
to inspire the students, right?
要激勵大家，對嗎？
-No. -Huh?
-不是 -什麼？
I meant what I said.
我說的都是真心話
You don't need to go to UTokyo!
不用去什麼東大！
Why would you…
你怎麼這樣…
I'm telling you it's worthless.
我告訴你們，那根本沒用
UTokyo, that is.
要進東大啊
It's easy to get in if you know how.
只要知道方法就很簡單
Look at Mizuno. She's stupid and ugly.
看看水野，她又笨又醜
Well, she isn't ugly, but she was truly stupid.
好吧，她不醜，但她以前真的很笨
But she got into UTokyo!
但連她都能進東大了！
There are techniques to get in!
進入東大是有方法的！
If you just study using them,
如果學會這些方法
a few of you could get into UTokyo.
你們之中會有幾位進入東大
But I don't think it's worth it for you!
但我不覺得你們有這價值
You all seem lazy and slow.
你們全部都看起來又懶又遲鈍
Your studies and school life are all half-assed.
無論學習或是校園生活 你們都是半吊子
Messing with phones and games all day.
整天只會玩手機和遊戲
Just sleepwalking through each day.
每天都在耍蠢和夢遊
You're all idiots! If only you were just idiots.
你們全都是笨蛋！ 如果你們只是笨蛋還好
Indifferent, apathetic, spoiled, and gutless.
平庸、有氣無力、被慣得毫無膽量
You want to go out into the world as you are now?
想這個樣子進入現實社會？
You'll be swallowed by the swirling drainpipe of society.
你們會被社會的漩渦吞噬掉
Before you know it, you'll be exploited, deceived, duped, and abused.
在你們意識到之前 已經被剝削、欺騙、愚弄、虐待
You'll be a slave to society all your life and struggle until you die.
這輩子都會是社會的奴隸 掙扎到死的那一天
If you don't want that,
如果不想這樣
There is a quick and easy way.
有個快而簡單的方法
Go to UTokyo.
上東大
But I can't imagine you have enough value!
但我不覺得你們有這價值！
Pretending to be human, while you're not even thinking.
人模人樣，其實連思考都不會
UTokyo doesn't want you!
東大才不要你們！
What were you thinking? Destroying my speech.
你在想什麼？這樣破壞我的演講
Destroy? Quite the opposite.
破壞？應該是相反吧
They ignored you, but they all listened to me.
他們無視妳，但都聽我說話
That may be true, but if you say that, nobody will come.
這麼說可能沒錯 但你這樣說，沒人會來的
If we don't get five students into UTokyo, we're fired.
如果無法把五位學生送進東大 我們就會被開除
Finding a way to make that happen is your job.
找方法實現它，那是妳的工作
Mr. Sakuragi! Ms. Mizuno!
櫻木老師！水野老師！
Can I see you in the staff room?
我們能到辦公室談談嗎？
Mizuno will go.
水野會過去
-Huh? -Oh, where is the Special Course room?
-啊？ -對了，專科課室在哪裡？
The empty room on the third floor.
在三樓的空教室
Okay.
好
Hey, that big dude was pretty funny.
話說，那個大塊頭還蠻好笑的啊
Stop talking about him.
別再說他了
Why not? It seems fun, the UTokyo Special Course.
為什麼？東大專科聽起來很好玩啊
Are you two interested in UTokyo?
妳們兩位對東大有興趣嗎？
Kaede!
楓！
Are you alright?
妳沒事吧？
Thank you.
謝謝
Let's go.
走吧
Kaede! What's wrong?
楓！妳怎麼了？
I got a cramp.
我抽筋了
-Can I help you stretch it? -I'm okay.
-我幫妳拉一拉好嗎？ -我沒事
You're okay?
妳還好嗎？
-How is it? -Look.
-怎麼樣？ -妳看
-Oh good! -What!
-太好了！ -什麼嘛！
-Let's go. -Yeah.
-走吧 -嗯
Forget about UTokyo.
忘了東大吧
Especially you.
尤其是妳
I was never interested.
我從來沒感興趣過
UTokyo? I hate those stuck-up jerks.
東大？我最討厭那些自大的白痴
Me too.
我也是
Huh?
什麼？
People who think they won life because they went to UTokyo.
那些以為自己進了東大 就是人生贏家的人
People who act servile as soon as they meet someone from UTokyo.
那些遇到東大生 就表現得卑躬屈膝的人
They're all sleazebags.
那都是卑鄙下流的人
So why UTokyo then?
那為什麼還要去東大？
You know what?
那個嘛
You kids are too young to understand.
你們這些孩子還太年輕，不會懂的
What?! Isn't that the opposite of what you just said?
什麼？這不是 和你剛剛說的完全相反嗎？
You just want to diss everything.
你只是要來批評一切
You come here to get a kick out of making fun of students?
你來這裡就是為了看學生笑話嗎？
I should ask you.
那我問你
What value do you have?
你有什麼價值？
And what value do you have?
那妳又有什麼價值？
Don't you know?
你不知道嗎？
Hang on, sir. Kaede has a mountain of value!
等一下，老師 楓的價值不是開玩笑的！
She's a national-level badminton player.
她是國家級的羽毛球手
-She's been scouted by top universities. -Nao!
-頂尖大學都想招她入學 -菜緒！
So that's why you aren't interested in UTokyo.
所以妳才對東大不感興趣
Don't worry. UTokyo isn't interested in you either.
放心好了，東大對妳也不感興趣
And in a few months, those other universities
過幾個月，那些其他大學
won't be interested either.
也不會對妳感興趣
Let's go, Kaede.
走吧，楓
What gives? He's a creep.
說什麼啊？真是個怪人
What?
幹嘛？
What's this?
這是什麼？
A list of students who could get into UTokyo.
有可能進入東大的學生名單
A list? It's just two people.
名單？上面只有兩個人啊
Don't say that.
別這麼說嘛
Our top of science is Ryo Fujii from Class 5.
理科第一名是五班的藤井遼
An incident on exam day forced him to come here.
他在大考那天發生了意外 才來了我們學校
His grades are high, and he could have a shot at UTokyo.
他的分數很高，有機會進入東大
Yes?
什麼事？
Fujii, do you want to try for UTokyo?
藤井，你要試試看東大嗎？
I've heard you could do it…
我聽說你可以…
I do plan to try for UTokyo.
我是有試試東大的打算
Really? Well then…
真的？那麼…
But I don't plan to join your course.
但我沒打算加入老師的課程
If I study with those idiots, I might catch it.
和這些笨蛋一起學習，我可能會染上
The stupidity.
他們的愚蠢
The second is the top of arts, Mari Kosugi from Class 7.
第二位是文科的第一名 七班的小杉麻里
She has excellent grades.
她學業成績很好
But she is not interested in university.
但對大學沒興趣
She wants to get a job after graduation.
打算畢業後直接找工作
Um, Mari Kosugi?
那個，小杉麻里？
That's me.
是我
-Uh, UTokyo… -I'm not interested in UTokyo.
-那個，東大… -我對東大沒興趣
I'm in a hurry.
我趕時間
Hey, Kenta.
等一下，健太
Wow! So this is the famous badminton team.
哇！這就是那有名的女子羽球社？
This is the only thing we're top-level at.
這是我們唯一全國頂尖的事
They placed second at the Inter-high last year.
去年的校際比賽，他們得了亞軍
Iwasaki and Kiyono, "Iwa-Kiyo" are popular in school too.
岩崎和清野的岩清組合 在校內也很出名
Especially the ace, Kaede Iwasaki.
特別是王牌岩崎楓
They say she has a shot at the Olympics.
據說她有機會參加奧運會
She's super talented.
非常有才華
Stop practice. Let's greet the vice principal and Ms. Mizuno.
暫停練習 和教務主任還有水野老師打招呼
Yes!
是！
-Hello. -Hello!
-你們好 -你們好！
Wow, so polite.
哇，真有禮貌
Mr. Miyamura, sorry I interrupted.
宮村老師，不好意思 打斷你們的練習
Okay, get some water and restart.
好了，去喝點水再繼續訓練吧
Yes!
是！
You can do it!
加油！
-Oh, Iwasaki. -Yes?
-對了，岩崎 -是
How are you feeling?
妳感覺怎麼樣？
I'm in great condition.
狀態很好
Good luck at the spring tourney. But don't push too hard.
春季錦標賽加油哦 但別把自己逼得太緊了
Thank you.
謝謝
Ms. Mizuno, um…
水野老師，那個…
It's about Mr. Sakuragi.
關於櫻木老師
Yeah? What is it?
嗯？怎麼了？
Oh, it's nothing. Excuse me.
沒什麼事，我先走了
I wonder if Iwasaki is interested in the Special Course?
不知道岩崎對專科感不感興趣？
She already heard from a top team, Seinan University.
她已經收到了西南大學的邀請
They want her on a sports recommendation.
他們讓她透過體育推薦入學
At any rate, UTokyo's not for her.
不管怎麼看，東大都不適合她
You're right.
你說得對
There are other students with guts who are promising.
我們去看看其他 有決心又有潛力的學生
What are you doing, Iwasaki?!
妳在幹嘛，岩崎？
Fifty burpees.
50個立臥撐跳
Okay.
是
1, 2…
一、二…
You're off your game today.
妳今天狀態不好啊
I blame him. Sakuragi.
都怪那個人，櫻木
He might expose my shoplifting.
他可能會把我偷東西的事傳出去
Did he threaten you?
他威脅妳了嗎？
He said in a few months, my recommendations will dry up.
他說幾個月後 那些大學就會對我沒興趣了
No applicants today…
結果今天沒有人申請啊
You're not moving in here, are you?
什麼？你該不會搬進來了吧？
You said there was a place to sleep.
是妳說這裡有地方睡覺的
Not here! Students come here!
這裡不行，學生會來這裡的
-Will they? -They will.
-真的會嗎？ -會啊
I'll go get five right now.
我現在就去找五個來
Oh look, here's a course hopeful now.
你看，這不就來了個希望嗎？
Kosugi, I knew it!
小杉，我就知道！
Come in!
請進！
Hey…
咦？
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
Take your time…
妳慢慢來
We're less popular than an insect.
昆蟲都比我們受歡迎
You just watch.
你等著瞧吧
Students will rush in asking to get into UTokyo.
那些學生會衝進來，求著要進東大
Look. This time for sure.
你看，這次肯定是了吧
Huh?
啊？
Is this…
這是…
the UTokyo Special Course?
東大專科？
Yes it is, but why?
對，怎麼了？
Please! We want to get into UTokyo!
拜託了！我們想進東大！
Mr. Sakuragi!
櫻木老師！
Sir!
老師！
We got our first two applicants!
我們有兩個人報名了！
S-Sir?
老…老師？
Anyway, come in.
那個，進來吧
A giant stag beetle.
鹿角甲蟲？
Yeah.
嗯
-It's huge. -No!
-好大隻啊 -不可以！
Mr. Sakuragi.
櫻木老師
It was hard to speak up at school, so…
剛剛在學校有點難開口
Um…
那個…
Is it truly easy to get into UTokyo?
進東大真的很容易嗎？
What are the odds?
機率有多大？
What are your specific study methods?
你說的特別學習方法是什麼？
You said we're not worth going to UTokyo.
你說我們不配去東大
What sort of person is worthy?
那什麼樣的人才配去呢？
Ms. Tamura says you've got problems.
田村老師說你有一些問題
What sort of problems? I searched online but I couldn't…
是什麼問題？我上網查了，但找不…
Can you swim?
你會游泳嗎？
I'm not good at the crawl.
我不擅長自由泳
But I can breaststroke 25 meters in 23 seconds.
但能在23秒內蛙泳25公尺
W-What are you doing?!
你…你幹嘛？
Feels good, doesn't it?
感覺很好，對吧？
Hey!
喂！
Hey! Don't leave!
喂！別走！
At least pull me up! Hey!
至少把我拉上去啊！喂！
How's our teacher, senpai?
前輩，我們老師過得怎樣？
Stop calling me senpai. We got into UTokyo together.
別再叫我“前輩”了 我們一起進東大的
A senpai in high school is always a senpai.
高中的前輩永遠都是前輩
Forget that. What about Mr. Sakuragi?
別說那個了，櫻木老師怎麼樣？
Awful. He ruined the opening ceremonies.
糟透了，他搞砸了開學典禮
When students come, he ignores them and goes away.
學生來找我們，他不理他們就走開了
Plus Mr. UTokyo himself is saying, "Don't go to UTokyo."
而且這個東大先生 自己把“別去東大”掛在嘴邊
He changed so much in two years.
他在兩年內變了好多
That incident two years ago must've really affected him.
兩年前的事真的影響他很深
-I guess. -I don't really get it.
-我想是吧 -我不明白
It's hardly online at all.
網路上都幾乎找不到
I've got all the baseless facts here.
我這有一些沒有根據的事實
Hey, was that student really the cause?
我說，那個學生真的是原因嗎？
Yoneyama?
米山？
Yeah, that kid.
對，那個孩子
That day, two years ago.
兩年前的那天
I can't forget that day.
我沒辦法忘記那天
Excuse me.
打擾了
-How many? -Of eight, seven passed.
-多少位？ -八位中有七位通過了
Oh…
這樣啊
You're not happy? That school has a deviation score of 45.
你不滿意嗎？ 那間學校的平均分數只有45分
Seven at once is great!
一次過通過七位，很厲害啦！
-Who failed? -It was Yoneyama.
-誰沒通過？ -米山
You'll get lots of education consulting work now!
你很快會收到很多教學顧問的工作了
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Kishimoto, don't make me say it.
岸本，說真的
I'm not a teacher. I'm a lawyer.
我不是老師，我是個律師
It's not so simple.
才沒有那麼簡單
Schools from around the nation will want you to be their education consultant.
全國的學校 都會想要你當他們的教學顧問
As manager of this office, I can't ignore them.
作為事務所的經營者 我不能就這樣無視他們
You just produced amazing results.
你才剛創造出那麼出色的成績
One failed.
失敗了一個
Just one!
只有一個！
You still look down. Eat something nice and cheer up.
你看來心情還是不怎麼好 去吃點好吃的打起精神來
-Where are we going? -I found a good place.
-去哪？ -我找了個好地方
It has two Michelin stars.
有米其林二星
We can walk from here.
這裡走過去就到了
-There it is. -Ah.
-我們到啦 -啊
Sir?
老師？
Go on ahead.
妳們先進去
Hello? Yoneyama?
喂？米山？
-Sir… -Hello?
-老師 -喂？
-Sir!
-老師！
Sir!
老師！
Yoneyama.
米山
Where's Yoneyama?
米山在哪？
My son…
我的兒子…
How could this happen?
怎麼會這樣？
The University of Tokyo?
東京大學？
He could've just graduated,
他本來可以好好畢業
and gone to a fine university, and had a good life.
去一個好大學，快快樂樂地生活
Why did you tell him to go to UTokyo?
為什麼你要讓他上東大？
Why UTokyo?
為什麼要去東大？
Somehow the news got out.
消息不知道怎麼傳了出去
All the tabloid shows and magazines in the country were abuzz.
國內的新聞媒體都在議論紛紛
Don't you think it was the mother? Who leaked it.
不覺得洩露出去的人是他的母親嗎？
Right? That's still the biggest mystery.
對吧？這是目前最大的謎點
Why?
為什麼？
To do that would mean to expose her son to public opinion.
這麼做會把她的兒子曝露在輿論之下
Would she really?
她會這麼做嗎？
At any rate,
無論如何
Mr. Sakuragi's reputation plummeted after that.
櫻木老師的名聲大跌
But why didn't he fight back?
但是，他為什麼不反擊？
You were right with him. You should've.
妳那時就在他身邊，妳應該反擊的
I had planned to.
我有打算這麼做
But the day he was discharged,
但他出院的那天
I went to get him, and the room was empty.
我去接他，他的房間已經空了
His house as well. I still don't know where he went.
他家也是 我到現在都不知道他那時去了哪裡
I see…
原來如此
The lawyer he built his career with, Kishimoto, she must've been shocked.
和老師共事的岸本律師一定很震驚吧
She's a strong person.
她是個堅強的人
Kaori Kishimoto Law Office…
岸本香法律事務所
Toranomon, district 7, that's just around the corner.
虎之門第七區，就在這裡附近
I had no choice. Mr. Sakuragi is missing.
我沒辦法了，櫻木先生失蹤了
I'm closing this place, and taking over the clients.
我要關掉這裡，把客戶接到我這
And I'll need your help.
我需要妳的幫忙
You'll stay, right?
妳會留下來吧？
But you didn't stay.
但妳沒有留下來
I felt responsible for Yoneyama.
我覺得自己對米山有責任
And I felt bad for Mr. Sakuragi.
也虧欠了櫻木老師
He changed my life.
他改變了我的人生
Even if he's… like this now.
就算他變成現在這個樣子…
Now you'll have to be his leader.
那現在輪到妳來帶領他了
First, make sure you don't lose the two students who joined your course.
首先，一定不要失去 那兩個剛加入專科的學生
If he sees the students working hard,
對，看到學生在努力
maybe he'll get motivated too.
他可能也會被動搖呢
Yeah.
嗯
This week, char siu noodles, normally 900 yen,
平日900圓的叉燒麵
are 800 yen, a discount of 100 yen!
這週只要800圓，折扣100圓！
Char siu noodles are cheap this week?
叉燒麵這週有優惠嗎？
Yes, they're very good.
有，很好吃哦
-Okay, I'll have that. -Yes.
-好，我要點那個 -好的
-One char siu noodle. -Okay!
-叉燒麵一份 -好！
Thank you for waiting, here is your order.
久等了，你的叉燒麵
Sir.
老師
We met in front of the store. I'm Akira Seto from Class 1.
我們在便利商店前見過 我是一班的瀨戶輝
Oh!
哦！
"Setoya."
“瀨戶家”
-Is it your parents' shop? -It used to be.
-這是你父母的店嗎？ -曾經是的
They died in an accident, and now my sister runs it.
但他們在一場意外中去世了 現在由我和姐姐來經營
Hey sis. This is Mr. Sakuragi from school.
姐，這是學校的櫻木老師
Thanks for teaching my brother.
我弟弟承蒙你照顧了
She's working hard.
她很努力工作
When I graduate, I want to take over.
畢業後，我想把店接過來
Hey, you're not aiming for UTokyo, are you?
哥，你該不會想考東大吧？
-What? -That teacher who threw you in the sea.
-什麼？ -那個把你丟進海裡的人
He's Sakuragi, who got all those kids into UTokyo.
就是把很多學生送到東大的櫻木吧？
-Why… -My old classmate at Tatsumi told me.
-你怎麼知道… -我唸龍海的同學告訴我的
Why did you go to talk to him?
你為什麼去找他？
-I, uh… -Hang on.
-那個… -等一下
Your dumb ass trying for UTokyo?
就憑你這種腦袋也想進東大？
Of course not.
當然不是
I wanted to get advice for your UTokyo entrance exams.
我想幫你問問看 東大入學考試有什麼要注意的
Huh.
這樣啊
That's a lie.
騙人
I'm home!
我回來了！
-Yuta. Don't tell Mom. -Yuta, I'll make dinner now!
-裕太，不要告訴媽媽 -裕太，我做晚餐了哦
Tell me the truth.
跟我說真話
If you don't, I'm telling.
你不說真話，我就跟她說了
Tell me.
說啊
Tell me!
說啊！
We'll do all of this today.
今天，我們要把這些全都做完！
What's wrong? Are you scared?
怎麼啦？怕了嗎？
Uh, no.
呃，沒有
I'm so happy you're being strict.
我很高興妳那麼嚴格
Huh?
啊？
We know we have to work ten times as hard to get into UTokyo.
我們很清楚 得用十倍努力才能進東大
So we're glad.
所以，我們很樂意！
-I'll do it! -I'll do it.
-我會做的！ -我會做的
Kohashi… Iwai…
小橋、岩井
There's no point in getting motivated.
有動力是沒用的
This is class time.
現在是上課時間
Isn't it mean to say there's no point?
你說沒用，是不是太刻薄了點？
That sort of motivation breaks easily.
這種動力很容易就會被打斷
Hey, Sir!
喂，老師！
-Sorry, that teacher is always sleeping. -Ma'am.
-對不起，那老師總是在睡覺 -老師
Please.
拜託妳了
Shave our heads.
剃掉我們的頭髮吧
-But… -People always judge us on our looks.
-但是… -大家總是以貌取人
We take pride in our hair color.
我們對自己的髮色感到驕傲
But other people just see us as punks.
其他人卻只是 把我們當成不良少年而已
But you didn't abandon us and tried to see us face-to-face.
但水野老師沒放棄我們 還試著和我們面對面談
That makes me pretty happy.
這讓我很開心
We're not concerned about our hair now.
我們現在不關心頭髮了
Only UTokyo.
只關注東大
We want to get into UTokyo, and show everyone.
我們要考進東大，讓所有人瞧瞧
Got it. Let's show everyone together.
我明白了，我們一起讓他們瞧瞧
Okay!
-好！
Yeah, yeah! Iwai, it's great!
好，很好！岩井，太棒了！
Ma'am, get right in there.
老師，妳過來一點
-Please! -Okay!
-拜託了 -好！
MIZUNO FORCES STUDENTS TO SHAVE HAIR
（東大專科的水野強迫學生剃頭）
But…
這個是…
That video was uploaded to a video site several days ago.
這影片前幾天被上傳到網路
Goodness gracious.
我的天啊
How behind the times could the UTokyo Special Course possibly be?!
東大專科到底是什麼年代的教育？
It was the students' own request…
那是學生自己要求的…
Those two would never say such a thing.
他們不可能會說那種話
They're troublemakers.
他們只會對老師惡作劇
No…
不是吧
-Mr. Tsuji? -Yes.
-辻老師 -是
And this is you, Mr. Sakuragi, isn't it?
還有這是你吧，櫻木老師？
Yes.
對
It's me, without a doubt.
就是我，千真萬確
Horrible! How could you…
不可理喻！你怎麼可以…
Now, now!
這…
There must have been educational intentions, right?
這之中一定有什麼教育意圖，對吧？
Intentions?
意圖？
Nothing of the sort.
沒這種東西
Can you even call yourself a teacher? Answer me!
你還能稱自己是教師嗎？回答我！
Ms. Tamura.
田村老師
I'll bring this up at the next board meeting.
我會把這些帶到下次理事會議
We'll also discuss whether you should stay or leave.
我們也會討論你到底是去是留
Okay.
好
You've got no proof, have you?
妳沒有證據，對吧？
But that shaving video.
但那支剃頭的影片
You said you were filming to remember the day.
你們說只是拍來作紀念
Just like that, we're criminals?
這樣而已，我們就是罪犯了？
Isn't this harassment? Wanna take a video?
這算是騷擾嗎？要再拍一部影片嗎？
Hey there!
你們！
You're really behind the times.
老師，妳真的很落伍
Your speech at the opening ceremonies made me laugh.
妳在開學典禮的演講很可笑
"You can do it if you try." That doesn't fly with us.
“只要願意，你就做得到” 我們不吃這一套
You lied about wanting to go to UTokyo?
你們說要上東大都是假的？
-Of course I did! -You really are naive.
-當然了！ -妳真的好天真！
Even UTokyo can't fix stupid.
連東大都補救不了的蠢
You might be doing this as a joke.
你們這樣做可能覺得好玩
But I truly meant to send you to UTokyo.
但我是真的想要把你們送到東大
You're wrong in the head.
妳腦子有問題吧
Someone changed my life by helping me get into UTokyo.
曾經有一個人 他幫我考進東大，改變了我的人生
And now I want to change yours.
我也想要改變你們的
And so you want to fix the video problem.
所以妳想解決那支影片的問題？
Of course I do.
我當然想
In order to invite us here,
為了把我們請過來
there are teachers who risked their careers.
有些老師賭上了他們的事業
We have to produce successful UTokyo candidates.
我們一定要培訓出 成功考進東大的人選
Oh okay, in that case…
哦，原來是這樣啊
"I'm very sorry! I went too far."
“很抱歉，我做得太過火了”
If you bow down your head, I'll think about it.
如果妳這樣鞠躬道歉，我就考慮一下
Do it. Quickly.
做啊，快點
Hurry!
快啊！
Do it!
道歉！
I'm very sorry.
很抱歉
I went too far.
我做得太過火了
Alright! We got it!
好，拍到了！
But here's my answer.
但是，這是我的答覆
We don't know anything about the video!
影片的事，我什麼都不知道！
And we don't care about UTokyo!
我們也不在乎什麼東大！
I did what you said and now this?
我照你們說的做了 你們現在這樣對我？
Don't mess with me. You rotten idiots.
別惹我！你們這些爛透的白痴
I withdraw my offer!
我收回剛剛的話！
Scary! Let's post a video of the abusive teacher's real feelings.
好可怕！施虐狂老師真情流露 快拍個影片傳出去
Stop! Abuse! Ow!
住手！虐待啊！好痛！
Your lives are shit.
你們的人生就是一坨屎
Sir…
老師
Wasting time.
浪費時間
Are you lecturing me?
你是在和我說教嗎？
Hey! What are you doing? Give it back!
喂，你在幹嘛？還回來！
What? Oh! Whoa!
喂，什麼？喂！
What are you doing?!
你在幹什麼？
Ow, ow, ow…
啊，好痛…
If you think an adult wouldn't hurt a child, you're mistaken.
如果你覺得大人不會打小孩 你就錯了
Go ahead, punch me! Hey, Iwai!
來啊，打我啊！岩井
Can teachers punch students?
教師可以打學生嗎？
It's corporal punishment.
這是體罰
I'm not a teacher.
我又不是教師
I'm a lawyer.
我是個律師
Sir!
老師！
Hey, let's go. Hurry!
喂，走吧，快點！
They really will fire you.
他們真的會開除你
I'd prefer to be fired.
我蠻想被開除的
I'd be out of here in a flash.
我馬上就能走
I can't get a good sleep in.
我在這裡睡不好
Let me sleep in peace.
讓我安靜睡個覺吧！
You can't accept defeat.
妳真是不能接受失敗啊
You say it was a setup. Where's the proof?
妳說別人陷害妳，證據呢？
I'm saying, if you ask those two…
所以說，妳可以去問問他們兩個…
I already asked. They said they were forced.
我已經問了，他們說是被逼的
And you believed them?
妳相信他們？
Okay, let's say what you say is true.
好吧，就當妳說的是真的
Would they sacrifice their hair, which they valued a lot,
他們為什麼要犧牲那麼寶貝的頭髮
just to chase you out for no reason?
就為了把你們趕走？理由在哪？
Pardon me!
打擾了
I told you to never come in here again!
我跟你說過別再進來了！
I'm sorry, but I thought you should see this.
對不起，但我想妳需要看看這個
I'm very sorry. I went too far.
很抱歉，我做得太過火了
It's over for you two.
你們兩個完蛋了
What a beautiful view!
真是一片美景！
Why'd you do that?
你們幹嘛這麼做？
It's punishment for throwing Amano in!
這是把天野丟進海裡的懲罰
Your face wasn't shown clearly in the shot.
你的臉在影片裡不清楚
This time we got it.
現在我們能拍清楚了
-Do it. -Okay.
-喂 -好
Apologize for throwing Amano in the sea.
為把天野丟進海裡道歉
There's one more apology.
不，還有另一個
Yoneyama too.
也給米山道歉
Apologize to them and I'll help you.
跟他們兩個道歉，我就拉你上來
How does my apology benefit you?
我道歉對你們有什麼好處？
We'll be heroes
我們會成為英雄啊
if we get the asshole who drove his student to near suicide to apologize.
讓那個把學生逼到自殺的混帳道歉
Hurry and apologize. "Sorry for driving you nearly to suicide."
趕緊道歉啊 “對不起，把你逼到自殺
"I'm sorry for injuring my student."
我對傷害學生很抱歉”
What'll you do if I drown out here?
我在這裡淹死了 你們會有什麼後果？
That'll just be treated as suicide.
那只會被當作自殺而已
You've got a checkered past.
誰叫你有一段黑歷史
Idiots, don't think you'll get away with this.
白痴，不要覺得你們會沒事
We do think so, we do think that! There's no proof!
不是啊，我們真的這樣覺得！ 這裡沒有證據！
This time of day, nobody's here, and nobody's watching.
大白天的沒人在附近，也沒人在看
You've got two marks on your record. Nobody will listen to you.
你有兩次前科，沒人會相信你的
Idiot!
笨蛋！
Let's go.
走吧
Where is he? At such an important time.
這種重要的時候，他跑去哪了？
But it's just as the chairman said.
不過就像理事長說的
Why did those two do such a thing?
那兩個人為什麼要這麼做？
What's their reason for chasing us out?
他們為什麼要把我們趕出去？
"Important: Loan Repayment Demand Notice." Oh no.
“重要，還款要求通知”，糟了
"Your repayment date has passed, and you haven't paid."
“您的還款日期已過，但您還未付款
"If you do not pay,
若不及時還款
you will be charged a late fee, and your contract will be canceled."
我們將徵收逾期費 並終止您的合約”
Whoa, oh no. I'm going out of business.
什麼？大事不妙，我們要倒閉了
What'll happen to him?
他會怎麼樣？
Huh? He's fine, he can swim to shore.
啊？不會有事的，他會自己游上岸
I guess.
我想也是
Why are you scared? He's probably taking a bath right now.
你怕什麼？他可能正在洗澡呢
Sakuragi?
櫻木？
You mock adults.
你們戲弄大人
You think you're better than everyone?
以為自己比其他人優秀？
If you do, you're true idiots.
如果你們真的這樣認為 你們就是真正的白痴
What are you doing?!
你在幹嘛？
If you can't stop teens from smoking, you should go under.
如果無法阻止未成年人吸菸 你至少應該藏起來
Don't forget.
不要忘了
The one punished under the Prohibition of Minors' Smoking law,
《禁止未成年人吸菸法》懲罰的
is the adult that didn't stop them.
是那些沒能阻止他們的大人
It's unfair, ain't it?
很不公平，對吧？
Hey, you two, out of here.
喂，你們兩個，給我出去
Hurry, get out.
快點，出去
Let's go.
走吧
Kohashi!
小橋！
You asshole…
混帳
Hey, what're you gonna do about your bike?
喂，你的機車怎麼辦？
I'll ask the barkeep what happened.
我過後再問酒吧老闆
Stop at the next store.
在下一間店停下來
Okay.
好
Hey, look!
喂，你看！
Go! Go, go, go!
走！快！
Weren't you in favor of the Special Course?
你不是贊成開辦東大專科嗎？
Yes…
對
Then why did you bring me this video?
那為什麼給我這支影片？
I merely want to be useful to you.
我只是想幫助理事長妳
I don't understand.
我不明白！
Why did you betray me then?
那你為什麼背叛我？
Tell me the reason.
告訴我原因
Could it be…
難道…
Sakuragi has dirt on you?
櫻木有你的把柄？
I knew it.
我就知道
What does he know?
他知道些什麼？
I can't say.
我不能說
-Tell me. -I can't!
-告訴我 -我不能！
-Hurry and tell me! -I cant!
-趕快告訴我！
-Go in! -Huh?
-進去！ -啊？
Go to the school!
轉進去學校！
What's that sound?
這是什麼聲音？
Whoa, whoa!
喂！
Out of the way!
讓開！
Help us!
救救我們！
Someone! Someone!
來人啊！
When you try to threaten someone, do your research.
威脅人之前，勸你們還是先做點調查
I'm a former biker.
我以前是暴走族
What's with that? Trying to say you used to be tough?
說這個幹嘛？ 是想表達你曾經很強嗎？
Still am.
現在還是
Stop with the bad jokes!
別再開玩笑了！
You still think an adult won't hurt a kid?
你們還是覺得 成年人就不會傷害小孩嗎？
E-Everyone, film this.
大…大家，快把這拍下來
What are you doing?! Get your cameras out!
還等什麼？快把手機拿出來！
Look, it's proof. Proof!
看，這就是證據！
You swing that, it's going to the police. Got it?
你敢再晃，這影片就會 作為證據交給警察，你明白了嗎？
You feel good, threatening an adult with that?
這樣威脅大人，你很爽嗎？
Your lives really are shit.
你們的人生真是一坨屎
S-Stop.
停…停手
The eyes of shitty slackers like you, stay rotten even when you're an adult.
看看你們這種懶鬼的眼睛 成年了還是會繼續腐爛
Hitting and insulting people.
到處打人、挑釁人
Yet you always claim your own rights.
卻總會主張自己的權利
Dragging down people trying to live seriously.
拖垮那些認真生活的人
You'll become trash adults.
你們長大後會變成垃圾
People like you could even kill someone trying to live properly.
像你們這樣的人 甚至會殺死想要好好生活的人
Scary times.
恐怖時間到
So long!
再見！
Sir!
老師！
Hey, everyone stop filming.
好了，大家，別拍了
-Phones are against the rules. -Out of the way now.
-校規上說不能帶手機 -讓開一下
Mr. Sakuragi!
櫻木老師！
What's going on? What did you do to my students?
發生什麼事？ 你對我的學生幹了什麼？
Pee! Mari! Pee-pee!
尿！麻里，妳看，尿！
Pee! Pee!
尿！
Stop… stop…
不要…
Stop! Stop!
不要！
Don't film.
不要拍！
How about it?
怎麼樣？
Beaten down by violence.
被暴力打敗
Being laughed at and ridiculed. How is it?
被當笑話看，感覺怎麼樣？
Dominating with power, and with words, it's both violence.
用力量支配他人是暴力 用語言支配他人也是暴力！
Tricking people and trapping them with phones and social media is violence!
用手機、社群軟體玩弄他人 陷害他人是暴力！
Mizuno, you said you wanted to change them.
水野，妳說妳想改變他們
But that's wrong.
但那是錯的
The only ones who can change their shit lives is them.
唯一能改變他們屎一樣人生的 只有他們自己
They have to wake up on their own!
他們得自己醒來！
No matter the reason, teaching with violence is unacceptable.
不管什麼原因，都不能用暴力來教育
They're children. Adults have to protect them.
他們是孩子，大人應該保護他們！
Are you saying kids can get away with anything?
妳是說，孩子就可以為所欲為嗎？
Even this?
就連這樣也可以嗎？
What a beautiful view!
真是一片美景！
How'd you…
你怎麼…
Smartphones sure are handy, right?
智慧手機真的很方便，對吧？
If you don't have video and sound, you're behind the times, right?
不會拍片和錄音就落伍了，對吧？
Respecting a child's freedom isn't the same as spoiling him!
尊重孩子的自由不代表慣壞他們！
Not scolding their mistakes, not giving them goals.
不責備他們的錯誤，不給他們定目標
That's why these kids
難怪這些孩子
have eyes like dirty ditchwater!
眼神和溝渠的臭水沒兩樣！
Calling it freedom, you're not protecting students.
妳說的自由並沒有保護這些學生
It's your own positions!
那只是妳的自說自話而已！
You're just avoiding responsibility and problems!
妳不過是在逃避責任，逃避問題！
You two.
你們兩個
Listen carefully.
給我聽清楚
Don't think you'll be forgiven just because you're kids.
不要以為自己是小孩 無論做什麼壞事都會被原諒
Kids or weaklings.
你們是孩子還是弱者？
Get carried away and you'll be crushed easily.
再這樣得意忘形 你們很快就會被粉碎
Don't underestimate society!
別小看現實社會了！
I'll do the same thing as you, yeah.
我會和你們做一樣的事情
Are you putting the pee video on social media?
你要把失禁的影片放上社群軟體？
-How do I… -Stop, please!
-我要怎麼… -停手，求求你！
-Ms. Mizuno! -We admit we framed you.
-水野老師 -我們承認我們陷害了妳
Forgive us!
求求你們原諒我們！
If you bow down your head, I'll think about it.
如果你們低頭道歉，我就考慮考慮
We're very sorry!
-我們真的很抱歉！
Now I understand what happened.
我明白情況了
Principal.
校長
Principal! Take them to the nurse's room.
校長！帶他們去醫務室
Huh? Okay.
啊？好
Stand up. Okay, stand up.
站起來，好了，站起來
Pardon me.
不好意思
However, your violence has not gone unnoticed.
儘管如此 我們不能就這樣放過你的暴力行為
Throwing a student into the sea is violence.
把學生丟進海裡是暴力
You're misunderstanding.
妳誤會了
He jumped in with me.
老師和我一起跳了進去
Hey! Don't leave!
喂！別走啊！
At least pull me up! Hey!
至少把我拉上去啊！喂！
Don't leave! Hey!
別走！喂！
That's cold.
好冷
Don't mull it over. Jump in.
別在邊緣試探，直接跳進去
It might have been my imagination,
那可能只是我的錯覺
but I felt like he was telling me to try applying to UTokyo.
但我感覺他好像在告訴我 去試試看申請東大
I decided to make a move without thinking.
於是我決定不想太多，直接行動
I want to join the UTokyo Special Course.
我…想參加東大專科
I want to learn from Mr. Sakuragi.
我想向櫻木老師學習
So there's no problem, right?
所以沒有問題了，對嗎？
It was all a misunderstanding.
那都是一場誤會
There are students who want to join.
有學生願意加入專科
You are never again to do things that could be misunderstood.
你絕對不能再做這種令人誤會的事
Time to go, it's over.
沒事了，大家解散吧
Sir, thank you so much.
老師，謝謝你
Don't misunderstand. I just want to sleep in peace.
不要誤會，我只想睡個好覺而已
Oh, right.
哦，對了
This is important, here.
這很重要，拿去
Where are you…
咦？你要去哪？
Huh? I'm returning this.
啊？我要去還這個
Wow, sir. That really cleared my head.
老師你真厲害，我茅塞頓開了
He's trouble. If he has dirt on us,
被他抓到弱點的下場也太慘了
this is really bad.
不能再更糟了
You told us to get rid of Sakuragi.
你叫我們把櫻木處理掉
He really put us through it.
但他把我們搞成這樣
I'm too embarrassed to go to school now.
真丟臉，我連學校都不想去了
Are you listening?
你在聽嗎？
Tossing him in the sea was too far.
把他丟進海裡太過火了
Like I said.
像我之前說的
You should've stopped at sharing the videos.
拍完影片後就該停手了
I think a Tatsumi student forgot to pay.
有位龍海的學生好像忘了付錢
Huh?
啊？
This is just a token of apology.
這算是道歉
I can't take that.
我不能收
Also, could you show me that?
對了，你可以讓我看看那個嗎？
A receipt for 5,000 yen? "Survey expense"?
五千圓的收據？“調查費用”？
An invoice?
帳單？
A hundred thousand yen?! What is all this?
十…十萬？這都是什麼？
No. No, no, no.
不好了…
Is that what happened? Well you got a new student.
聽說妳有了個新學生，是真的嗎？
I know you can bring Mr. Sakuragi back, senpai.
我就知道前輩能把櫻木老師帶回來
There you go again, calling me that.
你又來了，又叫我前輩
Anyway, I'll do what I can.
無論如何，我盡力吧
Oh, sorry, my meeting is starting.
不好意思，我要去開會了
Okay, I got it. Thanks for everything.
知道了，謝謝你做的一切
Okay, bye.
好，再見
Good work today.
辛苦了
Are these the papers you wanted?
這些是你要的資料嗎？
Oh, thank you.
啊，謝謝
Mr. Sakuragi might be back.
櫻木老師可能要復職了
Huh. Is that right?
啊，真的嗎？
That's…
那可是…
a perfect chance to destroy them.
毀掉他們的完美機會
Sir!
老師！
You massive idiot!
你這個大白痴！
I can't just quit.
我不能就這樣放棄
How will I live my life?
我要怎麼活下去？
What you do is up to you.
妳要怎麼做，妳來決定
I will crush them.
我絕對會毀掉他們
The Special Course is done for.
這個專科完了
I can't just stand by.
我不能只是在旁邊看著
Leave it.
別管了
My life will be ruined.
我的人生會被毀掉
You're a failure as a human!
你根本不配當人！
Subtitle translation by: Claire Tanaka
字幕翻譯：楊易